<idea-plugin>
    <id>ai.korasafe.jetbrains</id>
    <name>KoraSafe Governance</name>
    <vendor email="Contact-us@korasafe.ai" url="https://korasafe.ai">KoraSafe</vendor>

    <description><![CDATA[
        <p>
          KoraSafe Governance runs AI-specific governance checks every time you save.
          It catches the patterns that block a regulated launch: leaked API keys, PII
          in prompts, LLM calls shipped without error handling, destructive actions
          without a human approval gate, missing rate limits on routes that hit an LLM.
        </p>

        <p>
          Part of <a href="https://korasafe.ai">KoraSafe</a>, the AI governance
          intelligence platform for compliance, security, and GRC teams.
        </p>

        <h3>What it catches</h3>
        <ul>
          <li><b>Secrets.</b> Anthropic, OpenAI, AWS, GitHub, Slack, JWT tokens, and hardcoded credential strings.</li>
          <li><b>PII.</b> Social Security numbers, credit card numbers, emails, phone numbers in code literals.</li>
          <li><b>LLM calls.</b> Direct SDK calls to Anthropic, OpenAI, Bedrock, Vertex, Cohere, and generic <code>client.invoke</code> / <code>model.generate</code> patterns.</li>
          <li><b>Destructive actions.</b> <code>execute()</code>, database <code>.delete()</code>, deploys, file writes, network <code>.send()</code> patterns.</li>
          <li><b>Missing human-in-the-loop gates.</b> Flags destructive actions that ship without an approval or consent path nearby.</li>
          <li><b>Missing error handling.</b> LLM calls outside a <code>try</code>/<code>catch</code> wrapper.</li>
          <li><b>Missing rate limits.</b> API endpoints that hit an LLM without any rate-limit primitive in scope.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>Where findings show up</h3>
        <ul>
          <li>KoraSafe tool window on the right rail, grouped by severity.</li>
          <li>Inline inspections that underline the offending range and surface in the Problems tool window.</li>
          <li>Intention actions on Alt+Enter (Option+Return on macOS) with quick fixes and regulation references.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>Cloud governance (opt-in)</h3>
        <p>
          Set an API key and the plugin layers regulation mapping (EU AI Act, GDPR, NIST AI RMF), organization policy
          sync, and evidence-bundle export on top of the local checks. Cloud checks are off by default. A confirmation
          dialog runs before the first cloud call. Files above the configured size limit are skipped. Untrusted
          projects never trigger cloud checks regardless of settings.
        </p>

        <h3>Supported IDEs</h3>
        <p>
          IntelliJ IDEA, PyCharm, WebStorm, GoLand, RubyMine, AppCode. Baseline platform IntelliJ 2024.2
          (<code>since-build=242</code>).
        </p>

        <h3>Privacy</h3>
        <p>
          Nothing leaves your machine by default. Cloud checks and telemetry are both opt-in. Read the
          <a href="https://korasafe.ai/privacy/jetbrains-extension">privacy policy</a> before enabling either.
        </p>
    ]]></description>

    <change-notes><![CDATA[
        <h3>0.2.0</h3>
        <ul>
          <li>First public release on JetBrains Marketplace.</li>
          <li>Local governance rules: secrets, PII, LLM calls, destructive actions, missing HITL gates, missing error handling, missing rate limits.</li>
          <li>KoraSafe tool window, inline inspections, intention actions.</li>
          <li>Opt-in cloud checks with EU AI Act, GDPR, NIST AI RMF regulation mapping.</li>
          <li>Local MCP server for MCP-capable assistants.</li>
          <li>Signed evidence-bundle export.</li>
          <li>OTLP trace export.</li>
        </ul>
    ]]></change-notes>

    <idea-version since-build="242" until-build="243.*"/>

    <depends>com.intellij.modules.platform</depends>

    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
        <notificationGroup id="KoraSafe" displayType="BALLOON"/>
        <toolWindow id="KoraSafe"
                    anchor="right"
                    factoryClass="ai.korasafe.plugin.KoraSafeToolWindowFactory"/>
        <localInspection implementationClass="ai.korasafe.plugin.KoraSafeInspection"
                         shortName="KoraSafeGovernance"
                         displayName="KoraSafe governance findings"
                         groupPath="KoraSafe"
                         enabledByDefault="true"
                         level="WARNING"/>
        <intentionAction>
            <className>ai.korasafe.plugin.KoraSafeIntentionAction</className>
        </intentionAction>
    </extensions>

    <actions>
        <action id="KoraSafe.ScanCurrentFile"
                class="ai.korasafe.plugin.KoraSafeScanAction"
                text="KoraSafe: Scan Current File"
                description="Run KoraSafe governance checks on the current file"/>
    </actions>
</idea-plugin>
